Shahriar Yazdipour



Software Engineer and Data Scientist Phone: +49 1631932054 Germany (from 2019) yazdipour@outlook.com linkedin.com/in/yazdipour/ Skype: sh.yazdipour

www.yazdipour.com

Profile

Shahriar (Sha) spent the past two years getting his Computer Science MSc in TU Ilmenau and also working as a Java Back-end Software Developer in TomTom Berlin.

Dealing with Machine Learning projects in Academia and Backend Service Development is his current job. Previously, he spent 2 years as an Android Developer at a startup. Also he develops open source C# applications in his free time.

EDUCATION

Masters, Computer Science & Systems Engineering

2019 - 2022

Technische Universitat Ilmenau *Thuringia, Germany*

Bachelor, Computer Science

2013 - 2018

Kharazmi University *Tehran, Iran*

Work Experience

• BackEnd Software Engineer Intern at 'TomTom' - Berlin, Germany:

Aug 2020 - Now

- o Main Task: Delivering services in the field of traffic information, tested and applied in the real-production system.
- o Working in Agile environment with daily standups and Jira Kanban discussions.
- Programming a Java Spring Web Service for TPEG2-EAW and TPEG2-EVA.
- o Developing Java Quarkus MQTT Pub/Sub Service.
- o Customizing and deploying VernemQ MQTT Broker.
- o Deployment on Microsoft Azure Cloud and AKS Kubernetes Cluster.

• Android Software Engineer at 'GFPishro Co' - Tehran, Iran:

Oct 2017-Jan 2019

- Main Task: Creating a Geo Information Service/Software-Package, including Web, Desktop and Mobile applications for our customer.
- Developing Java / Android Mapping system based on MapsForge renderer system, graphhopper offline navigation for our customers using IntrAnet.
- o Developing Simple Reporting Application for Client in iOS Xamarin Forms with C#.
- o Using Visual Studio App Center for CI/CD pipeline.

SKILLS & EXPERIENCES

• Programming Languages:

- Python (PyTorch, Huggingface, Keras, Flask, Web3, PyAutoGui, ...)
- Java (Quarkus, Spring, Android, Swing,...)
- **C#** (Xamarin, UWP, WPF, .NET,...)
- o C++/Arduino and Some Front-End Experience.
- Tools: Git, Microsoft Azure, Docker, Kubernetes
- Databases/QLs: MySql, SQLite, Neo4j, SparQL

• Text-to-SPARQL Question Answering Transformer (NL2Script):

Aug 2021

- Task: Implementation of sentence embedding for learning the transformation of questions to SPARQL queries with DBPedia WikiData data integration in **Google T5 and BERT Transformer**.
- o Pre-processing and collecting a data-set with specific features needed.
- o Implement Fine Tuning steps for T5 Language model using Pytorch.
- Developing a pipeline from data to deploying the model to Huggingface repositories.

• Covid-19 Opinion Leaders on Twitter - Data Mining and Graph Analysis:

Sep 2020

- Task: Identifying opinion leaders in Twitter using social network Graph Analysis methods.
- Pre-processing 300GB twitter data-set with specific features using Dask.py (parallel computing library).
- Using Social network analysis methods to find opinion leaders with NetworkX Python library.

• Developed MIRA Robot navigation system:

Dec 2019

- \circ OpticalFlow and Color Segmentation Navigation using its camera system with C++
- o Object Detection using ResNet, ImageNet architecture with Pytorch

• Recommendation System for Student Applicants, Seeking Financial Scholarship for Studying Abroad:

2017

- We have implemented a technique to bypass vBulletin CMS authentication system to crawl unstructured raw data from it and provide a dataset
- Using data analysis methods such as Decision tree, K-Nearest Neighbor and K-Means to determine chance of getting fund for graduate students.

Wireless Garage Door Cracker

Capturing sub-1 GHz signals with RTL-SDR and Analyzing with GQRX and sending signals with YardStick1.

Jul 2017

• UWP Applications (First Persian UWP Developer):

2015 - 2016

- Developed iTehran which is the First Persian UWP application.
- Developed multiple WPF and UWP application with more than 30,000 users download overall.
- o Used MVVM, Xaml and C# and multiple Database systems.
- o Designed UI and Logo using Adobe XD and Photoshop.

PUBLICATIONS

Github Data Exposure using GraphQL Security Design Flaw (1k\$ Bug Bounty)

2019

S. Yazdipour*, CCSE2020 - The 10th International Conference on Computer Engineering, Ilmenau Germany

[Published]

Decision Support for International Students Who Want to Fund Their Graduate Studies

2017

S. Yazdipour*, N. Taherian "(IEEE) International Conference on Machine Learning and Data Science, India"

[Published]

CERTIFICATIONS (GITHUB.COM/YAZDIPOUR/CERTIFICATES)

- Structuring Machine Learning Projects-Coursera
- NLP with Python for Machine Learning Lynda
- Web Security from Shahid Beheshti University
- Artificial Intelligence Foundations Lynda

- Python Beginner to Advanced from Udemy
- Microservices Foundations from Lynda
- CCNA from CyberTech
- NetworkPlus from CyberTech